BRIAN K. WONG

917-815-2243 | bwong92@gmail.com | Website | GitHub | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

My software development journey began while obtaining my MS in Accounting. After learning to code taking data analytics courses, I immersed myself in software development learning Ruby, Javascript, and frameworks to create full-stack applications. I look forward to bringing my experience working in Accounting as part of a team and problem-solving discipline into software development

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Abibas - Github | App

Built an application that allows users to purchase sporting goods online

- Designed and created database schema and RESTular API with Active Record, Postgres, Ruby on Rails
- Leveraged Redux and middleware for asynchronous data retrieval from the back end
- Utilized local storage, JWT Auth, and custom validations to create authorization and authentication for users
- Developed the Frontend utilizing Vanilla HTML/CSS to enhance presentation and enhance user experience

Better Than Trello - Github | App

A simple application built over 2-3 days that allows users to organize their projects

- Designed and created database schema and RESTular API with Active Record, Postgres, Ruby on Rails
- Utilized React and Vanilla CSS to build out the front end to ensure smooth user experience

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, Git, CSS, HTML

Familiar with: Python, Java, React Native, AngularJS, Typescript

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Y Stem & Chess Inc | Jr. Developer

Dec 2020-Present

- Developing and maintaining a web application used to teach children with Asperger's Syndrome Chess
- Working with a team of four people to develop web application using AngularJS and Typescript
- Participate in weekly stand-ups and contribute to ideas/features

NYC Coders Hackathon for Black Lives Matter | Jr. Developer/Hacker

June 2020

- Attended a 4-day event to develop solutions and bring awareness to the Black Lives Matter movement
- Collaborated with a team of 5 to produce a data visualization dashboard that displays NYC police shooting data
- Created components and structured the layout of the dashboard in React to demonstrate how clear the data is skewed

OTHER EXPERIENCE

SL Group, Brooklyn, NY | Private Equity Intern

Feb 2018-June 2018

- Identified and prepared summaries for private middle-sized companies that met the desired attributes for acquisition
- Provided financial statement analysis to assess targeted companies' business structure, as well as DCF's to project company outlook over 5 year period

Kings County Public Administrator, Brooklyn, NY | Accounting Consulting Intern

July 2017-Jan 2018

- Collaborated with a team to troubleshoot, reorganize, and establish internal controls to improve accounting procedures increasing a general fund from less than \$50K to over \$1M and better manage assets of a fiduciary fund of \$100M
- Reviewed high volume of data in documentation to verify accuracy of passed financial statements (going back four years) to reconstruct them for compliance with Governmental Accounting Standards Board

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY | Fullstack program (SQL, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Active Record, Javascript, React, Redux) **Baruch College, Zicklin School of Business, New York, NY** | Master of Science: Accounting | GPA: 3.3 **SUNY Buffalo, School of Management, Buffalo, NY** | Bachelor of Science: Accounting

Dec 2019 May 2019 May 2015